[{"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", "."], "qSentId": 4, "question": "What steps should I take right now to set myself up for financial success?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "NNS", "MD", "PRP", "VB", "RB", "RB", "TO", "VB", "PRP", "RP", "IN", "JJ", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 5, "answer": "Investments.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "NNP", ",", "NNS", "CC", "NNS", ",", "CC", "DT", "NN", "NNS", "IN", "DT", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 12, "question": "How do I start preparing for my retirement?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WRB", "VBP", "PRP", "VB", "VBG", "IN", "PRP$", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 13, "answer": "Suze Orman, dollars and cents, and the hottest issues of the day.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["DT", "NN", "''", ":", "PRP", "VBP", ",", "PRP", "VBP", "RB", "RB", "VBN", "TO", "NN", "IN", "DT", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 28, "question": "Ryan, why are you so opposed to gay people getting married?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "WRB", "VBP", "PRP", "RB", "VBD", "TO", "VB", "NNS", "VBG", "JJ", "."], "aSentId": 29, "answer": "A DEFENSE\": You know, I'm not really opposed to anything in this situation.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "IN", "NN", "IN", "VBG", "DT", "NNS", "VBP", "DT", "NN", "TO", "VB", "TO", "DT", "NN", "NN", "CC", "NN", "IN", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 37, "question": "Are you in favor of gay marriage?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "PRP", "IN", "NN", "IN", "NN", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 38, "answer": "I'm in favor of having the citizens have the authority to go to the ballot box and vote about marriage.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "IN", "NN", "IN", "NN", "IN", "DT", "NN", "CC", "DT", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 48, "question": "Are you in favor or against gay marriage?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "PRP", "IN", "NN", "CC", "IN", "NN", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 49, "answer": "I'm in favor of marriage between a man and a woman.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "RB", "VB", "PRP", "VBZ", "RB", "IN", "."], "qSentId": 58, "question": "That basically the reason a man and a woman should be allowed to marry rather than a man and a man or a woman and a woman, is to do with their ability to procreate?", "question_pos_tagged": ["DT", "RB", "DT", "NN", "DT", "NN", "CC", "DT", "NN", "MD", "VB", "VBN", "TO", "VB", "RB", "IN", "DT", "NN", "CC", "DT", "NN", "CC", "DT", "NN", "CC", "DT", "NN", ",", "VBZ", "TO", "VB", "IN", "PRP$", "NN", "TO", "VB", "."], "aSentId": 59, "answer": "I don't think it's only that.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["DT", "VBZ", "NN", "IN", "PRP", "."], "qSentId": 61, "question": "Is that part of it?", "question_pos_tagged": ["VBZ", "IN", "NN", "IN", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 62, "answer": "That's part of it.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["DT", "."], "qSentId": 65, "question": "So would you ban everyone over the age of 50 from getting married?", "question_pos_tagged": ["IN", "MD", "PRP", "VB", "NN", "IN", "DT", "NN", "IN", "CD", "IN", "VBG", "VBN", "."], "aSentId": 66, "answer": "No.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {"ORGANIZATION": ["Supreme Court"]}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["DT", "NNP", "NNP", "VBD", "IN", "DT", "NNS", "IN", "DT", "JJ", "NN", "TO", "VB", "IN", "NNS", "CC", "PRP", "VBD", "RB", "IN", "IN", "WP", "NN", "VBZ", ",", "VBZ", "DT", "NN", "IN", "DT", "NN", "CC", "DT", "NN", ",", "NNS", "VBP", "IN", "JJ", "NN", "RB", "IN", "PRP", "VBP", "RP", "IN", "NN", "CC", "PRP", "RB", "VBP", "NNS", "."], "qSentId": 91, "question": "Is your answer to that question yes?", "question_pos_tagged": ["VBZ", "PRP$", "NN", "TO", "DT", "NN", "VBZ", "."], "aSentId": 92, "answer": "The Supreme Court looked at these cases of the fundamental right to marry for prisoners and they understood again because of what marriage is, is a union of a man and a woman, prisoners have that same right partly because they come out of jail and they still have lives.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "NN", "IN", "PRP", ",", "CC", "PRP", "MD", "VB", "PRP", "WRB", "."], "qSentId": 135, "question": "What it boils down to?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "PRP", "VBZ", "RP", "TO", "."], "aSentId": 136, "answer": "I feel compassion for you, and I'll tell you why.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {"ORGANIZATION": ["Supreme Court"]}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["DT", "NNP", "VBZ", "RB", ",", "WDT", "VBZ", "WRB", "DT", "NNP", "NNP", "MD", "RB", "VB", "IN", "."], "qSentId": 161, "question": "Where does the American Constitution say that a same-sex couple can't get married?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WRB", "VBZ", "DT", "NNP", "NNP", "VBP", "IN", "DT", "JJ", "NN", "MD", "RB", "VB", "VBN", "."], "aSentId": 162, "answer": "The Constitution doesn't, which is why the Supreme Court shouldn't say that.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["CC", "VBP", "RB", "VB", "TO", "VB", "TO", "VB", ":", "PRP", "VBP", "DT", "VBP", "JJ", "NNS", "."], "qSentId": 224, "question": "Do -- is that what you think is going to happen?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ":", "VBZ", "IN", "WP", "PRP", "VBP", "VBZ", "VBG", "TO", "VB", "."], "aSentId": 225, "answer": "But don't want to have to obscure -- I think these are secondary issues.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["IN", "WRB", "VBP", "PRP", "RB", "DT", "NN", "IN", "PRP", "MD", "RB", "VB", "VBN", "."], "qSentId": 231, "question": "Why?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WRB", "."], "aSentId": 232, "answer": "So how do we strengthen the message that they shouldn't get divorced.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["CC", "NN", "VBZ", "WP", "NNS", "DT", "NN", "CC", "DT", "NN", "IN", "DT", "JJ", "IN", "DT", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 252, "question": "What if you were sterile and you couldn't have a child?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "IN", "PRP", "VBD", "JJ", "CC", "PRP", "MD", "RB", "VB", "DT", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 253, "answer": "And marriage is what connects the mother and the father with each other for the child.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": [":", "PRP", "MD", "VB", "DT", "NN", "IN", "IN", "DT", "NN", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 260, "question": "Really?", "question_pos_tagged": ["RB", "."], "aSentId": 261, "answer": "-- we can have the government out of the marriage system.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {"LOCATION": ["America"]}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "IN", "DT", "NN", "IN", "DT", "JJ", "NN", ",", "CC", "IN", "NNP", ",", "EX", "VBP", "NNS", "IN", "NNS", "WP", "VBP", "IN", "PRP", "."], "qSentId": 266, "question": "Really?", "question_pos_tagged": ["RB", "."], "aSentId": 267, "answer": "We're in the court of this public opinion, but in America, there are lots of people who agree with me.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "CD", "."], "qSentId": 272, "question": "How old are you?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WRB", "JJ", "VBP", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 273, "answer": "I'm 31.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBZ", ":", "PRP", "VBP", "IN", "DT", "NN", "PRP", "VBZ", "RBR", "IN", "PRP", "IN", "PRP", ",", "IN", "PRP", "VBP", "PRP", "IN", "JJ", "NN", ",", "DT", "NNS", "RB", "IN", "DT", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 318, "question": "Is it more of them than us?", "question_pos_tagged": ["VBZ", "PRP", "JJR", "IN", "PRP", "IN", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 319, "answer": "It's -- I think at this point it is more of them than us, if you define us as main street, the people possibly in this room.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "VBG", "TO", "VB", "IN", "DT", "VBZ", "JJ", "IN", "PRP", "VBP", "RB", "VB", "."], "qSentId": 342, "question": "So what's the interest rate of your student loans?", "question_pos_tagged": ["IN", "WP", "POS", "DT", "NN", "NN", "IN", "PRP$", "NN", "NNS", "."], "aSentId": 343, "answer": "I'm going to act like that's rhetorical because I don't know.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "RB", "RB", "PRP", "VBP", "DT", "NN", ":"], "qSentId": 376, "question": "Suze, what would you recommend?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "WP", "MD", "PRP", "VB", "."], "aSentId": 377, "answer": "Well, now here we have the argument --", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", "IN", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 379, "question": "OK?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NN", "."], "aSentId": 380, "answer": "Arguments over marriage.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", "."], "qSentId": 390, "question": "Is she?", "question_pos_tagged": ["VBZ", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 391, "answer": "Yes.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", ",", "PRP", "VBP", "."], "qSentId": 392, "question": "So that's why -- because -- do you feel -- and do you feel like you're OK?", "question_pos_tagged": ["IN", "IN", "POS", "WRB", ":", "IN", ":", "VBP", "PRP", "VB", ":", "CC", "VBP", "PRP", "VB", "IN", "PRP", "VBP", "NNP", "."], "aSentId": 393, "answer": "Yes, I do.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NN", "."], "qSentId": 403, "question": "Really?", "question_pos_tagged": ["RB", "."], "aSentId": 404, "answer": "OK.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", ",", "PRP", "VBP", "."], "qSentId": 425, "question": "So do you have more than one piece of real estate?", "question_pos_tagged": ["IN", "VBP", "PRP", "VB", "JJR", "IN", "CD", "NN", "IN", "JJ", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 426, "answer": "Yes, I do.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["CD", ",", "VBG", "TO", "VB", "CD", "."], "qSentId": 427, "question": "How many do you have?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WRB", "JJ", "VBP", "PRP", "VB", "."], "aSentId": 428, "answer": "Two, going to be three.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["IN", "CC", "IN", "."], "qSentId": 430, "question": "Are they really complicated, your taxes?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "PRP", "RB", "VBD", ",", "PRP$", "NNS", "."], "aSentId": 431, "answer": "On and off.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", "IN", ",", "PRP", "VBD", "TO", "VB", "CC", "PRP", "VBD", "TO", "VB", "TO", "VB", ",", "VB", "JJ", "NN", "IN", "CD", "."], "qSentId": 476, "question": "Fundamentally, is it getting older or younger now, the retirement age of most Americans?", "question_pos_tagged": ["RB", ",", "VBZ", "PRP", "VBG", "JJR", "CC", "JJR", "RB", ",", "DT", "NN", "NN", "IN", "JJS", "NNPS", "."], "aSentId": 477, "answer": "Years ago, I used to sit and I used to say to everybody, take Social Security at 62.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "DT", "IN", "PRP", "."], "qSentId": 499, "question": "You have piece for Tiger Woods?", "question_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "NN", "IN", "NNP", "NNPS", "."], "aSentId": 500, "answer": "I love this for him.", "question_ne_tagged": {"ORGANIZATION": ["Tiger Woods"]}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "IN", "VBD", "DT", "RB", ",", "RB", "JJ", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 511, "question": "What do you make of that as a marketing ploy?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "VBP", "PRP", "VB", "IN", "DT", "IN", "DT", "NN", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 512, "answer": "I think that was a very, very large mistake.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["RB", "VBZ", "WP", "PRP", "VBP", ",", "IN", "EX", "VBD", "RB", "DT", "NN", "TO", "VB", "RP", "NN", ",", "PRP", "VBZ", "RB", "."], "qSentId": 530, "question": "How do you recover from it?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WRB", "VBP", "PRP", "RB", "IN", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 531, "answer": "Here's what you understand, if there was ever a time to go through bankruptcy, it is now.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "PRP", "."], "qSentId": 548, "question": "What do you think about Cheryl Sandberg's new book \"Lean In\"?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WP", "VBP", "PRP", "VB", "IN", "NNP", "NNP", "POS", "JJ", "NN", "``", "JJ", "IN", "''", "."], "aSentId": 549, "answer": "Love it.", "question_ne_tagged": {"PERSON": ["Cheryl Sandberg"]}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "NN", "NN", "."], "qSentId": 572, "question": "But if it's a woman producer and she leaves your hotel room at 3:00 or 4:00 in the morning, what's everybody going to think?", "question_pos_tagged": ["CC", "IN", "PRP", "VBZ", "DT", "NN", "NN", "CC", "PRP", "VBZ", "PRP$", "NN", "NN", "IN", "CD", "CC", "CD", "IN", "DT", "NN", ",", "WP", "VBZ", "NN", "VBG", "TO", "VB", "."], "aSentId": 573, "answer": "Hard working girl.", "question_ne_tagged": {"TIME": ["4:00 in the morning"]}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "IN", "."], "qSentId": 589, "question": "Another glass ceiling gets chipped away?", "question_pos_tagged": ["DT", "NN", "NN", "VBZ", "VBN", "RB", "."], "aSentId": 590, "answer": "I love that.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["UH", ",", "RB", "RB", "RB", ",", "PRP", "MD", "RB", "RB", "VB", "PRP", "."], "qSentId": 617, "question": "Do you want to get married, by the way?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "PRP", "VB", "TO", "VB", "VBN", ",", "IN", "DT", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 618, "answer": "Oh, so badly here, I can't even tell you.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "PRP", "VBP", "TO", "JJ", "NN", "PRP", "WRB", "VBP", "PRP", "VBG", "TO", "VB", "DT", "NN", "IN", "PRP", "VBP", "VBG", "TO", "VB", "."], "qSentId": 639, "question": "And how would you suggest going about that?", "question_pos_tagged": ["CC", "WRB", "MD", "PRP", "VBP", "VBG", "IN", "DT", "."], "aSentId": 640, "answer": "Well, you have to first teach them where are they going to get this money that they're going to save.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNP", ",", "PRP", "VBP", "TO", "VB", "PRP", "."], "qSentId": 643, "question": "Why are you giving them an allowance?", "question_pos_tagged": ["WRB", "VBP", "PRP", "VBG", "PRP", "DT", "NN", "."], "aSentId": 644, "answer": "Well, they have to earn it.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["PRP", "VBP", "VBG", "."], "qSentId": 658, "question": "Are you saving money for you?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "PRP", "VBG", "NN", "IN", "PRP", "."], "aSentId": 659, "answer": "I am trying.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["NNS", ",", "NNPS", "VBP", "."], "qSentId": 677, "question": "Do Americans overspend?", "question_pos_tagged": ["NNP", "NNPS", "VB", "."], "aSentId": 678, "answer": "Yes, Americans overspend.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}, {"answer_ne_tagged": {}, "docId": "130326pmt", "answer_pos_tagged": ["DT", ",", "PRP", "VBP", ",", "RB", "RB", "TO", "VB", "IN", "PRP$", "NNS", "CC", "IN", "PRP$", "NNS", "."], "qSentId": 699, "question": "If I could get you to leave us with one overriding thought for all Americans tonight to think about money in a sensible way, what would you want it to be?", "question_pos_tagged": ["IN", "PRP", "MD", "VB", "PRP", "TO", "VB", "PRP", "IN", "CD", "VBG", "NN", "IN", "DT", "NNPS", "VBD", "TO", "VB", "IN", "NN", "IN", "DT", "JJ", "NN", ",", "WP", "MD", "PRP", "VB", "PRP", "TO", "VB", "."], "aSentId": 700, "answer": "That, you know, just seriously to live below your means but within your needs.", "question_ne_tagged": {}}]